Sylvia Beach Papers, 1887-1966 (bulk 1920s-1950s ): Finding Aid
Princeton University Library. Department of Rare Books and Special Collections.
- Series 6: Sylvia Beach's Circle and Collections, 1874-1999; 31 boxes (4 partial)
  - Artwork, 1874-1999; portions of 3 boxes
    - Michaux, Henri: Unidentified Watercolor, undated; 1 folder Watercolor
    - Thu, Mai: Three Children, undated; 1 folder Small painting
      Also includes a piece of board with a red stamp used by Mau Thu.
    - Unidentified Oil Painting of Two Boys, circa 1874; 1 folder Oil painting
      Inscription on the backside of the frame: "Souvenir de M. Leavaey. M. Goussel le 18 Mai 1874"
    - Unidentified Oil Painting of Green and Red Figure, 20th century; 1 folder
  - Author Readings: Sound Recordings, 1913-1955; 17 folders Phonograph records.
    - Apollinaire, Guillaume Reading Le Voyageur, Le Pont Mirabeau, and Marie, 1913; 1 folder Phonograph record (Folder 1)
    - Dennis, Frederick Beach, 1947; 1 folder Phonograph record (Folder 2)
    - Dévigne, Roger Reading Reflux and Valéry, Paul Reading Message aux États-Unis and Hélène ou La Reine Triste, undated; 1 folder Phonograph record (Folder 3)
    - Eliot, T. S. Reading The Hollow Men, 1934; 1 folder Phonograph record (Folder 4)
    - Eliot, T. S. Reading Four Quartets, undated; 1 folder Phonograph record (Folder 5)
      Contains 5 records which include: East Coker (Parts 1-3), Dry Salvages (Parts 1-3), and Little Gidding (Parts 1-4).
    - Eluard, Paul Reading La Victoire de Guernica and Novembre 1936, undated; 1 folder Phonograph record (Folder 6)
    - Joyce, James Reading from Ulysses (Aeolus Episode), 1924; 1 folder Phonograph record (Folder 7)
    - Joyce, James Reading from Ulysses, undated; 1 folder Phonograph record (Folder 8)
      Reverse side contains readings by Paul Valéry and Guillaume Apollinaire.
    - Joyce, James Reading Anna Livia Plurabelle, 1949; 1 folder Phonograph record (Folder 9)
    - Joyce, James Reading from Ulysses and Finnegans Wake in German, undated; 1 folder Phonograph record (Folder 10)
    - Joyce, James Reading from Finnegans Wake and Siobhan McKenna and Cyril Cusack Reading Anna Livia Plurabelle and Shem the Penman, undated; 1 folder Phonograph record (Folder 11)
    - Monnier, Adrienne Reading Remerciments aux Intellectuals Argentins, undated; 1 folder Phonograph record (Folder 12)
    - Moore, Marianne "Reading her Poems and Fables from La Fontaine", 1955; 1 folder Phonograph record (Folder 13)
    - Pleasure Dome: "An Audible Anthology of Modern Poetry Read by its Creators", 1949; 1 folder Phonograph record (Folder 14)
      Includes Marianne Moore, T. S. Eliot, William Carlos Williams, Ogden Nash, Dylan Thomas, and others.
    - Sitwell, Edith "Reading from her Poetry", 1955; 1 folder Phonograph record (Folder 15)
    - Stein, Gertrude "Reads from her Works", 1934-1935; 1 folder Phonograph record (Folder 16)
    - Notebook on Phonograph Records, undated; 1 folder Phonograph record (Folder 17)
  - Barkentin, Marjorie: Ulysses in Nighttown, 1959; 2 folders
    - Correspondence, 1959 June-July; 1 folder (Folder 1)
    - Clippings and Related Material, 1959; 1 folder (Folder 2)
  - Bennett, Arnold: Posters Advertising "Arnold Bennett on Ulysses " in Outlook, undated; 1 folder
  - Briggs, Thomas and Carlotta Welles, 1933-1949; 3 folders
    - Carlotta Welles Briggs: Notebook, 1947; 1 folder (Folder 3)
    - Thomas Briggs: Birth Announcement and Bus Pass, 1933-1945; 1 folder (Folder 4)
    - Thomas Briggs: News Clippings, 1949; 1 folder (Folder 5)
  - Bryher (Annie Winifred Ellerman) Typescript and Clippings, undated; portion of 1 folder (Folder 6)
  - Dodson, Owen: Proofs of "Power Long Ladder", 1946; 1 folder (Folder 7)
    Given to Sylvia Beach by Richard Wright.
  - Doolittle, Hilda, 1956 September 16-1961 October 15; 2 folders
    - News Clippings and Reviews, 1956 September 16-1960 May 25; 1 folder (Folder 8)
    - Obituary in Time, 1961 September 29-October 15; 1 folder (Folder 9)
  - Eliot, T.S., 1929 November 13-1961 April 9; 2 folders
    - T.S. Eliot to James Joyce, 1931 July 6; 1 folder (Folder 10)
      Autograph letter
    - Clippings and Book Jackets, 1929 November 13-1961 April 9; 1 folder (Folder 11)
  - Exhibits, 1957-1962; 10 boxes (3 partial)
    - Hommage á Commerce, Rome, 1958; 1 folder (Folder 12)
    - Les Années Vingt: Les Écrivains Américains a Paris et Leurs Amis, 1959; 6 boxes (1 partial)
      - Correspondence, 1959; 6 folders (Folder 1-6)
      - Speeches and Related Material, 1959; 1 folder (Folder 7)
      - Catalogue Typescript, 1959; 1 folder (Folder 8-9)
      - Catalogues, Signed and Unsigned, 1959; 1 folder (Folder 1)
      - Radio and Television Appearances, 1959; 1 folder (Folder 2)
      - Publicity, 1959; 1 folder (Folder 3)
      - Poster, 1959; 1 folder
      - Photographs and Related Material, 1959; 1 folder (Folder 4-6)
      - Photographs, 1959; 1 folder (Folder 1-2)
      - Accounts and Related Material, 1959; 1 folder (Folder 3)
      - Appointments and Related Material, 1959; 1 folder (Folder 4)
      - News Clippings, 1959; 1 folder (Folder 5)
      - Opening, Guest List, 1959; 1 folder (Folder 6)
      - Notes, 1959; 1 folder (Folder 7)
      - Notes, 1959; 4 folders (Folder 1-4)
      - Memento File Case, 1959; 1 box
    - Paris in the Twenties, London, 1960; 2 boxes (1 partial)
      - Catalogue, 1960; 1 folder (Folder 1)
      - Invitations, 1960; 1 folder (Folder 2)
      - Invitations to Sylvia, 1960; 1 folder (Folder 3)
      - USIS, London, 1960; 1 folder (Folder 4)
      - Correspondence Regarding Lost Watch, 1960; 1 folder (Folder 5)
      - Guest Book and Guest Lists, 1960; 1 folder (Folder 6)
      - Travel, Hotels, Purchases, 1960; 1 folder (Folder 7)
      - Insurance, 1960; 1 folder (Folder 8)
      - Appointments, 1960; 1 folder (Folder 9)
      - Radio and Television Appearances, 1960; 1 folder (Folder 1)
      - London Trip Mementos, 1960; 1 folder (Folder 2)
      - Photographs, 1960; 1 folder (Folder 3)
      - Notes, 1960; 1 folder (Folder 4)
      - Oscar Wilde Theft, 1960; 1 folder (Folder 5)
    - Trois Amis du VIe, 1961; portions of 2 boxes
      - Catalogue, 1961; 1 folder (Folder 6)
      - Lists of Items, 1961; 1 folder (Folder 1)
      - Photographs, 1961; 1 folder (Folder 2)
      - Clippings, 1961; 1 folder (Folder 3)
    - Du Café Voltaire à la bibliothèque Benjamin Franklin, Paris, 1957; 1 folder (Folder 4)
    - The Nineteen Twenties, Paris, 1959; 1 folder (Folder 5)
    - Items Lent to Librairie la Hune, 1962; 1 folder (Folder 6)
  - Hemingway, Ernest, 1931-1964; portions of 2 boxes
    - "50,000 Dollars" Proofs, undated; 1 folder (Folder 7)
    - "War Poem" with Corrections, circa 1944 September 14; 1 folder Typescript (Folder 8)
    - Article in The Atlantic, 1954 March; 1 folder (Folder 9)
    - Article in The Commonwealth, 1961 September 22; 1 folder (Folder 10)
    - Article in Look, 1956 September 4; 1 folder (Folder 11)
    - Article in Actualité Littéraire, 1958 May; 1 folder (Folder 1)
    - Article in New Yorker, 1932; 1 folder (Folder 2)
    - Article in Johns Hopkins Magazine, 1961 October; 1 folder (Folder 3)
    - Articles in Life, 1954 November 8-1964 April 10; 1 folder (Folder 4)
    - Article in Paris Match, 1961 July; 1 folder (Folder 5)
    - News Clippings, 1938-1964; 1 folder (Folder 6)
    - News Clippings, 1944-1949; 1 folder (Folder 7)
    - News Clippings, 1949-1961; 1 folder (Folder 8)
    - News Clippings Regarding the Death of Hemingway, 1961 July; 1 folder (Folder 9)
    - News Clippings Regarding the Death of Hemingway, 1961 July; 1 folder (Folder 10)
    - Miscellaneous, 1931-1933; 1 folder (Folder 11)
  - Joyce, James, 1905 June 16-1967 November; 9 boxes (3 partial)
    - Portrait of the Artist, 1916-1954; 3 folders
      - Inquiry Re: Italian Translation, 1931 August; 1 folder (Folder 12)
        Includes note by James Joyce.
      - Inquiries, 1953-1954; 1 folder (Folder 13)
      - Press Notices, 1916; 1 folder (Folder 14)
    - Work in Progress and Finnegan's Wake, 1926-1959; 2 boxes (1 partial)
      - Work in Progress: Proofs for Installment in Transition, 1929; 1 folder (Folder 1)
      - Finnegans Wake Partial Typescript, undated; 1 folder 2 pages (Folder 2)
      - Finnegans Wake Manuscript Paragraph, undated; 1 folder (Folder 3)
      - Work in Progress: "Vocabulaire Européen" Booklet, undated; 1 folder (Folder 4)
        Inscribed: "Sylvia Beach for the study of Work in Progress by James Joyce this work by Ulysse Jourdain"
      - Review of a Fragment of James Joyce's "Work in Progress", undated; 1 folder
      - Work in Progress: Review by Cyril Connolly, Life and Letters, 1929; 1 folder (Folder 5)
      - Work in Progress: Inquiries, 1927-1931; 1 folder (Folder 6)
      - Finnegans Wake: Inquiries, 1934-1957; 1 folder (Folder 7)
      - Work in Progress Publisher Correspondence, 1926-1928; 1 folder (Folder 8)
      - Work in Progress: Publicity, 1929; 1 folder (Folder 9)
      - Finnegans Wake: News Clippings, 1931-1959; 1 folder (Folder 10)
    - James Joyce: Typescripts of Poems, "The Holy Office," "Molly Brannigan," and "Ecce Puer", 1932; 1 folder (Folder 1)
    - James Joyce: Manuscript of Poem, "Who is Sylvia", undated; 1 folder (Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 1905 June 16-1931 February 23; 7 folders
      - Establet, Antonin, Châteauneuf-du-Pape, 1930 January 22-May 6; 1 folder (Folder 3)
      - Gorman, Herbert, 1925; 1 folder (Folder 4)
      - Guinness, R.S., 1931 February 23; 1 folder (Folder 5)
      - O'Callaghan, Mary, 1927 November 24; 1 folder (Folder 6)
      - Richards, Grant, 1905 June 16; 1 folder Copy (Folder 7)
      - Wells, H.G., 1928 November 23; 1 folder Copy (Folder 8)
      - Copy of Letter by James Joyce Regarding "A Curious History", undated; 1 folder Copy (Folder 9)
    - Verbannte, by James Joyce, German Translation, 1919; 1 folder (Folder 10)
    - Miscellaneous Book Jackets, undated; 1 folder (Folder 11)
    - Mementos, undated; 1 folder (Folder 12)
      Includes play bills, notes, signs and pen nibs relating to Joyce.
    - Valuation and Sale of Joyce Collection, 1950-1967 November; 3 boxes (2 partial)
      - Description and Valuation of Joyce Collection, 1957; 1 folder (Folder 13-15)
      - University of Buffalo, 1950-1963; more than 11 folders
        - Bill of Sale of Sylvia Beach's Joyce Collection to Buffalo, 1959; 1 folder (Folder 1)
        - Notes, 1950-1959; 1 folder (Folder 2)
        - Exhibition of Joyce Collection at University of Buffalo, 1959; 1 folder (Folder 3)
        - Correspondence, 1958-1963; more than 7 folders
          - General Correspondence, 1959; 1 folder (Folder 4)
          - Legal Correspondence, 1959-1961; 1 folder (Folder 5)
          - Abbott Family, 1958-1960; 1 folder (Folder 6)
          - Silverman, Clare and Anne, 1961-1963; 1 folder (Folder 7)
          - Silverman, Oscar, 1958-1961; 1 folder (Folder 8-9)
          - Envelopes Which Contained Joyce Items Given to Oscar Silverman, Buffalo, undated; 1 folder (Folder 10)
          - Stafford, Constance and Budd, 1958-1960; 1 folder (Folder 11)
        - Inquiries, 1960; 1 folder (Folder 12)
      - The Philip H. & A. S. W. Rosenbach Foundation, "Notable Acquisitions: 1966-1967", 1967 November; 1 folder (Folder 1)
    - Articles and Criticism, 1917-1962; 3 boxes (2 partial)
      - Cohn, Alan M. (Joyce Scholar): Critical Articles, 1962; 1 folder (Folder 2)
      - Ellman, Richard, 1955-1961; 1 folder (Folder 3)
      - Gilbert, Stuart: Das Rätsel Ulysses, 1960; 1 folder (Folder 4)
      - Glasheen, Adaline, undated; 1 folder (Folder 5)
      - The Listener, 1946 October 24; 1 folder (Folder 6)
      - The Little Review, 1918 September-1920 August; 1 folder (Folder 7)
      - Magalaner, Marvin, 1956; 1 folder (Folder 8)
      - Mercanton, Jacques, undated; 1 folder (Folder 9)
      - Morse, J. Mitchell, 1955; 1 folder (Folder 10)
      - The New Republic, 1939 June 28; 1 folder (Folder 11)
      - Playboy, A Portfolio of Art and Satire, 1919; 1 folder (Folder 12)
      - Prescott, Joseph: Critical Articles on James Joyce, 1945-1956; 1 folder (Folder 1)
      - Saturday Review, 1950 April 29; 1 folder (Folder 2)
      - Time, 1934 January 29; 1 folder (Folder 3)
      - Time, 1950 August 7; 1 folder (Folder 4)
      - Tomorrow, 1949 December; 1 folder (Folder 5)
      - Vanity Fair, 1922; 1 folder (Folder 6)
      - Miscellaneous Articles, 1917-1951; 1 folder (Folder 7)
      - Miscellaneous Articles, 1928-1961; 1 folder (Folder 1)
    - The British Institute of Recorded Sound: Sylvia Beach on James Joyce, 1960 June 24; 1 folder 7" reel (1/4" magnetic tape) audio cassette (Folder 2)
    - Sylvia Beach on Inaccuracies in James Joyce Letters Edited by Stuart Gilbert, undated; 1 folder (Folder 3)
    - Mounted Poster for an Exposition in Honor of James Joyce, 1949 October-December; 1 folder
    - Sporting Times Poster Advertising "The Scandal of Ulysses ", undated; 1 folder
    - James Joyce Catalogue and List of Items for Sale, undated; 1 folder (Folder 4)
    - James Joyce Clippings, 1922-1966; 1 folder (Folder 5-7)
  - Joyce, Lucia, 1930-1961; 3 folders
    - Typescript of Autobiography and Advertisement for A.B.C. Chaucer, 1961; 1 folder (Folder 1)
    - Letter to Unknown Correspondent, circa 1930; 1 folder (Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous, 1960; 1 folder (Folder 3)
      Includes Easter cards, Christmas cards, notes, and a cloth made in Northern Ireland.
  - The James Joyce Society, 1956; 1 folder (Folder 4)
  - Larbaud, Valery Notes and Clippings, 1935 January 31-1957 February 8; 1 folder (Folder 5)
  - McAlmon, Robert, 1920 December-1932 March 10; portions of 2 boxes
    - Being Geniuses Together (Manuscript) and A Hasty Bunch (Proofs), undated; 1 folder Manuscript and proofs (Folder 6)
    - Contact Original Copy, undated; 1 folder (Folder 1)
      Due to the fragility of this edition, please consult curator before using the original. Use photocopies whenever possible.
    - Contact Correspondence, 1925 January 26-1932 March 10; 1 folder (Folder 2)
    - Contact Accounts, 1922 October 30-1928 October 1; 1 folder (Folder 3)
    - Contact Publications, undated; 1 folder (Folder 4)
    - Contact Review Edited by Robert McAlmon and William Carlos Williams, 1920 December; 1 folder (Folder 5)
    - Stormy Tea-Cups, undated; 1 folder Typescript (Folder 6)
    - Machine-Age Romance, undated; 1 folder Typescript (Folder 7)
  - La Maison des Amis des Livres, 1918-1956; portions of 2 boxes
    - Bookshop Catalogues, 1949; 1 folder (Folder 8)
    - Exposition of Paul-Emile Bécat, 1926-1927; 1 folder (Folder 9)
    - Posters for Exposition on Marie Monnier, undated; 1 folder
    - Sylvia Beach's La Maison Des Amis Des Livres Membership Card, 1918; 1 folder (Folder 10)
    - Mementos, undated; 1 folder (Folder 11)
    - La Gazette Des Amis des Livres, undated; 1 folder (Folder 12)
    - Valéry Larbaud on James Joyce, undated; 1 folder (Folder 13)
    - Lamy, Jacques, 1956; 1 folder (Folder 14)
      Jacques Lamy was the successor to Adrienne Monnier at La Maison des Amis des Livres.
  - Monnier, Adrienne, 1926-1961; 5 boxes (2 partial)
    - Design Drawings, undated; 1 folder (Folder 15)
    - Drafts and Manuscripts, undated; 1 folder (Folder 16)
    - La Nature de la France, undated; 1 folder Typescript (Folder 17)
    - Proof Sheets of Monnier's Preface to Bryher's " Beowulf, undated; 1 folder (Folder 18)
    - Notes for a Radio Talk by Sylvia Beach, undated; 1 folder (Folder 19)
    - Monnier, Adrienne to Holly Beach Dennis, 1960 March 16; 1 folder (Folder 1)
    - Monnier, Adrienne to Rinette (Marie Monnier-Bécat), 1938; 1 folder (Folder 2)
    - Monnier, Adrienne to Titivia, undated; 1 folder (Folder 3)
    - Monnier, Philiberte to Adrienne Monnier, 1940 August 10; 1 folder (Folder 4)
    - Comission Franco-Allemande, Décision, 1944 May 23; 1 folder (Folder 5)
      Order to undergo medical exam.
    - Health Notes, 1954; 1 folder (Folder 6)
    - Illness and Death of Adrienne Monnier, 1955; 1 folder (Folder 7)
    - Condolences on the Death of Adrienne Monnier, 1955; 1 folder (Folder 8)
    - Mementos, 1956-1961; 1 folder (Folder 9-11)
      Includes Adrienne Monnier's pens, a pocket knife, and a cigarette case given to Monnier by Sylvia Beach from Sarajevo.
    - Autographed Catalogue, Bibliothèque Particulière, 1926; 1 folder (Folder 12)
    - Club Maintenant Reading by Adrienne Monnier, "Aves les Poetes", undated; 1 folder (Folder 13)
    - News Clippings of Adrienne Monnier's Death, 1955 June; 1 folder (Folder 1)
    - Magazine Articles by Adrienne Monnier, 1930-1955; 1 folder (Folder 2)
    - Newspaper Articles by Adrienne Monnier, 1938-1954; 1 folder (Folder 3)
    - Magazine Articles about Adrienne Monnier, 1926-1948; 1 folder (Folder 4)
    - Newspaper Articles about Adrienne Monnier, 1960; 1 folder (Folder 5)
    - News Clippings, 1946-1960; 1 folder (Folder 1-3)
    - Notes on Adrienne Monnier, undated; 1 folder (Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous, 1935; 1 folder (Folder 5)
    - Literary Reviews, 1927-1955; 1 folder (Folder 1)
  - Monnier-Bécat, Marie (Rinette), 1927 June 4-1935; 4 folders
    - "Le Cerveau" Etching by Rinette (Marie Monnier-Bécat), undated; 1 folder (Folder 2)
    - Exhibit of Marie Monnier's Embroidery at La Maison des Amis des Livres, 1927 June 4; 1 folder (Folder 3)
    - Photos of Embroidery by Rinette (Marie Monnier-Bécat), 1935; 1 folder (Folder 4)
    - Photos of Rinette (Marie Monnier-Bécat), undated; 1 folder (Folder 5)
  - Porter, Katherine Anne, 1934 January 6-1964 August; 3 folders
    - Typescripts, 1934 January 6; 1 folder (Folder 6)
    - "Paris: A Little Incident in the Rue de l'Odéon," Ladies' Home Journal, 1964 August; 1 folder (Folder 7)
    - Clippings, 1935-1962; 1 folder (Folder 8)
  - Reverdy, Pierre: Manuscript of Poem "Bonne Chance" Dedicated to Sylvia Beach, 1951 January; 1 folder
  - Valéry, Paul, 1926-1957; 1 folder (Folder 9)
  - Weaver, Harriet, 1924-1961; 6 folders
    - Photographs, 1924-1960; 1 folder Photocopies of originals held in the Weaver estate. (Folder 1)
    - Correspondence Concerning Death of Harriet Weaver, 1961; 1 folder Photocopies of originals held in the Weaver estate. (Folder 2)
    - Rasmussen, Bjørn on Harriet Weaver, 1961; 1 folder Photocopies of originals held in the Weaver estate. (Folder 3)
    - Eye Shade Made by Harriet Weaver When She Visited Sylvia in Paris, undated; 1 folder Photocopies of originals held in the Weaver estate. (Folder 4)
    - Egoist Press Publications, undated; 1 folder Photocopies of originals held in the Weaver estate. (Folder 5)
    - Unidentified Envelope, undated; 1 folder Photocopies of originals held in the Weaver estate. (Folder 6)
  - Whitman, Walt, 1885 January 17-1886 August 30; portions of 2 boxes
    Contains framed scraps of Walt Whitman manuscripts rescued from a wastebasket by Sylvia Beach's aunt, Agnes Orbison, on a visit to Whitman in Camden.
    - Framed Autograph Manuscript, 1885 January 17; 1 folder (Folder 7)
      20 lines beginning: "The Leaves of Grass, simply the contribution of one Personality" and ends with: "It is not a candidate for the usual honors in that noblest of arenas, does not seek to meddle with literary rules and achievements."
      Reverse side contains letter written on a Brooklyn Daily Times letter-head by a Charles, but most of the letter is covered by the pieces of newspaper that Whitman pasted over it to strengthen the sheet of paper.
    - Framed Autograph Manuscript, 1885 February 23; 1 folder (Folder 8)
      17 lines, probably notes for a poem: "Songs have been sung- beautiful matchless songs adjusted to other lands, other days, another spirit and stage of evolution."
      Includes a letter to Walt Whitman from Willie N. Jones asking for an autograph on the reverse side.
    - Framed Autograph Manuscript, 1885 June 15; 1 folder (Folder 9)
      17 lines, apparently reflections on poetry and inspiration.
    - Framed Autograph Manuscript, 1886 August 30; 1 folder (Folder 10)
      Envelope addressed to Walt Whitman.
    - Framed Autograph Manuscript, undated; 1 folder (Folder 11)
      Manuscript, 12 lines, possibly notes for an essay on politics: "Given the Nineteenth Century with the United States and what they furnish as area and point of view..."
    - Framed Autograph Manuscript, undated; 1 folder (Folder 12)
      27 lines: "My own physical, emotional, moral, intellectual and esthetic Personality..."
    - Framed Autograph Manuscript, undated; 1 folder (Folder 1)
      16 lines and title "My Book and I": "After serious personal ambition as a young fellow..., rewards wordly, business, political, litterary...to take part in the great melee...I found myself remaining, at the age of 33..."
    - Articles and Pamphlets, undated; 1 folder (Folder 2-3)
  - Willard, Marian G., 1936 December 19-1944 September 7; 1 folder (Folder 4)
  - Wright, Richard, 1946 December 9-1963; 2 folders
    - The Man Who Lived Underground, 1946 December 9; 1 folder Typescript (Folder 5)
    - News Clippings, 1947-1963; 1 folder (Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous Art Shows, 1930-1960; 1 folder (Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous Periodicals, 1928-1962; 1 folder (Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous Poems, undated; 1 folder (Folder 2)
  - List of Books in Sylvia Beach Collection, 1964; 1 folder (Folder 3)
- Series 7: Photographs, 1881-1969; 14.1 linear feet 20 boxes
  This series consists of assorted photographs documenting the different facets and relationships central to Beach's life: her family; her friends, particularly Adrienne Monnier, but also including writers and artists; and her life in Paris as proprietress of Shakespeare and Company.
  Snapshot images and negatives (here defined as photographs lacking the formal approach of a studio portrait or news agency documentary photograph) measuring approximately 2.75 x 3.75 inches (7 x 10 centimeters) can often be attributed to Sylvia Beach herself. Images taken in and around Shakespeare and Company and Les Déserts are particular candidates for this attribution. However, photographer attributions were not given in this finding aid unless explicitly stated. Researchers should contact the estates of Man Ray, Gisèle Freund, Berenice Abbott and other copyrighted photographers present in the collection for information regarding copyrighted photographs.
  Arranged into 8 subseries.
  Access to the photographs is restricted because surrogates are available for reference use. Researchers who feel they have a compelling reason to be granted access to the original photographs must request permission in advance from the Curator of Manuscripts ( http://rbsc.princeton.edu/divisions/manuscripts-division ).
  - Subseries 7A: Beach Family Photographs, 1894-1969; 2.0 boxes
    This subseries consists of images of Sylvia Beach and her family. Images of immediate family members, including the creator’s parents Reverend Sylvester Beach, mother and sisters Holly and Cyprian Beach that date after Sylvia Beach began her independent life (circa 1914) are located elsewhere in the collection.
    This sub-series is organized by individual or family group in order of familial relationship to Sylvia Beach.
    - Photographs: Sylvia, Holly and Cyprian Beach as Children, 1894-1896; 1 folder (Folder 1)
    - Print: Cyprian Beach as Princeton "Prom" Girl, 1914; 1 folder (Folder 2)
      Given by Holly Beach Dennis in 1966
    - Photographs: Reverend Sylvester Beach, 1926-1939; Keystone View Company.; 1 folder (Folder 3)
    - Photographs: Mrs. Eleanor O. Beach, 1924; 1 folder (Folder 4)
    - Negatives: Mr. And Mrs. Beach, undated; 3 original negatives (Folder 1)
    - Photographs: Cyprian and Mrs. Beach, undated; 1 folder (Folder 5)
    - Photographs: Cyprian Beach, undated; Apers, Pierre; Geisler & Andrews.; 2 folders (Folder 6-7)
    - Photographs: Holly Beach Dennis, 1917-1960s; 2 folders (Folder 8-9)